# **MARISSA MELO**

MILPITAS CA 95035 408.807.5817 MARISSA.MELO91@YAHOO.COM

#### **PROFILE:**

Driven Production Planner/ Management Analyst with nine years of experience. Motivated team player with strong organizational and communication skills. Proficient at coordinating and managing business operations in a high-volume atmosphere. Seeking employment in a fast-paced environment where I can leverage my skills in accounting, purchasing, project scheduling, and production planning.

## **EXPERIENCE:**

## NASA Ames Research Center Production Planner/Supervisor

March 2013 - Present

- Manage and oversee planning and implementation of manufacturing and fabrication of flight hardware, ground support hardware and assemblies.
- Supervise ten contractors inspect and approve timecards, complete performance reviews and relay important company information.
- Generate, track, and archive all flight and ground support traveler packages for individual projects in the NASA Machining and Instrumentation Branch.
- Communicate status of quote packages as well as provide reports for customers.
- Input and track all service requests for the Manufacturing and Fabrication Shops.
- Review: drawings, project, specifications, and provide cost estimates for manufacturing with
  respects to technical capabilities. Provide technical knowledge for manufacturing concerns and
  provide necessary changes to guarantee conformity to NASA standards.
- Plan and manage in-house and contracted fabrication and manufacturing support. While
  ensuring that all statements of work adhere to NASA requirements as well as facilitating the
  logistics for various projects.
- Schedule and maintain manufacturing resources for multi-phase projects in support of Agencies missions and critical launch dates.
- Develop, coordinate, and schedule high-level reports and briefings for upper management and planning office staff to review project status, budgets, and discuss successes and challenges.
- Oversee Manufacturing and Fabrication Shops annual budget guidelines and generate budget reports for division to review quarterly.
- Analyze business operations, processes and provide new business strategies to improve productivity and efficiency with respect to annual budget allowance.
- Direct long-range plans for developing lines of new business to build and expand partnerships through Inter-agency partnerships as well as Space Act Agreement projects.

- Work with resource analysts to manage budgets and monitor project funds to ensure sufficient resources are available.
- Review and verify timecards ensuring correct tasks are being billed while monitoring project funds.

## **ASRC Federal (NASA Ames Research Center)**

**March 2013 – December 2013** 

- Managed flight and ground support hardware and inventory records.
- Handled shipping and receiving records.
- Handled transportation and delivery requirements.
- Managed drawing controls and job procurements
- Performed job scheduling and cost tracking.

#### **EDUCATION:**

- B.S., Organization Management, San Jose State University; 2009-2013
- High School Diploma, Milpitas High School, 2006-2009

## **TRAINING/ACCREDITATIONS**

• APPEAL Course and Scheduling Certification

January 2014

#### **PROFESSIONAL MEMBERSHIPS**

• State of California Bureau of Real Estate, Salesperson

**July 2016** 

#### **LANGUAGES**

- English- Fluent Oral, Reading & Written
- Portuguese Fluent Oral, Reading
- Spanish- Oral, Reading

# **AWARDS / RECOGNITIONS**

- NASA AMES Honor Award 2020
- **Group Achievement Awards** NASA Hybrid Wing Body Wind Tunnel Testing Team, NASA Rodent Research -1/-2, NASA EFT- Post flight Analysis & Avocet Extraction Team
- **Group Achievement Honor Award-** NAVAIR, LRASM Wind Tunnel Model Design and Manufacturing

#### **KEY WORDS**

Production Planner	Resource Analyst	Financial Management	Accounting
Buyer	Leadership	Budget	Procurement
Project Planner	Administrative Management	Data Entry and	Scheduling
		Timekeeping	